Muhammad Kashif Hussain

Objective Statement

To work with a well reputed, leading organization, having a competitive atmosphere and motivation for hard work & supporting research based practical knowledge to meet the ongoing and upcoming technologies. Apart from academia, I also gain team work and professional experience in different food industries (Multinational + National) and regulatory authorities of Provincial as well as National Scope. I equipped with more understanding about these organizations Cultures & procedures.

EDUCATION / Academic Record

2017-2019	M.Phil.
	M.Sc. (Hons.) Dairy Technology
	National Institute of Food Science and Technology
	University of Agriculture, Faisalabad (Pakistan)
Thesis Research	Title: -
	Comparative study of milk packed, before & after pasteurization, at lab scale.
2013-2013	Bachelors
	B.Sc. (Hons.) Food Science and Technology
	NIFSAT, University of Agriculture, Faisalabad (Pakistan)
2010-2013	Intermediate
	F.Sc. (Pre. Medical)
	Govt. Rizvia Islamia Post Graduate College Haroonabad
2008-2010	Matric
	Science
	Govt. Rizvia Islamia High School Haroonabad

Diploma /Certificate/ Trainings

December 2024	 Certified Lead Auditor FSSC 22000 V.6
2021/2022	Certified Halal Lead Auditor
2021/2022	Advance Diploma in Halal Food Safety and Audit (MHC, MUL Pakistan)
July 2020	 Unraveling Solutions for Future Food Problems
	(University of Utrecht Netherland)

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/03/2023 - Conti.

Dairy Specialist / Food Safety Officer

Islamabad Food Authority (Islamabad Capital Territory, Pakistan)

- Works to ensure safety and quality of foods to public of Islamabad Capital Territory, Pakistan
- Performed Special Duties to check and ensure safety of Food served to International Cricket Teams in Pakistan (New Zealand, Pakistan Super League, West Indies & Bangladesh)

01/11/2021-28-02-2023

TECHNICAL OPERATIONS HEAD

AShifa Food Pvt. Ltd. Lahore (Pakistan)

- Proactively development & act as a mentor for direct reporting.
- Installation and Management of Food Safety Management Systems (In House, Punjab Food Authority, PSQCA etc.)
- Developer & Manager at Halal Food Safety Management System (In House and RI & CA)
- To ensure all performance measures are monitored and recorded.
- Designing of Fruits and Vegetables Standards for internal procurements.
- Establishment of Laboratory System (Physic-O-Chemical & Microbiological)
- Food Safety & Handling Trainer
- Installation of OPRP, PRP, CCP's, ISO 17025, PAP, CAP

1/09/2019-31/10/2021

Food Technologist

AShifa Food Pvt. Ltd. Lahore (Pakistan)

- Installation of Food Safety Management System.
- Development and Maintenance of Food Testing Lab.
- Installment of Integrated Pest Management System.
- Work under Research and Development department for assigned tasks.

1/7/2017-31/08/2019

Quality Manager

Linka Foods Pvt. Ltd. Lahore (Pakistan)

- Developed QA & QC system for FMCG Company
- Develop and Install Food Safety and Quality Management system
- Develop Record keeping and Documentation System
- Develop and Install QA & QC Labs.

1/02/2017-31/04/2017

Internee

Pepsi-Cola International Pvt. Ltd. Lahore (Pakistan)

At Frito-Lay as food safety and quality control inspector of PepsiCo Pakistan

- Food Safety assurance

-Troubleshooting

29/10/2013-31/5/2019 Managements / General Management

- -Serve as a Team Head to Student's Club in UAF Pakistan
- Organized events under Qiraat and Naat Club- Seerat Chair UAF Pakistan
- Organized events under Sundas Foundation Lahore Pakistan
- -Organized different seminars and Conferences.
- Co-curricular activities of 4th Lyallpur Art & Lit. Festival 2016 in UAF Pakistan.

PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication skills

Excellent Communication Skills gained by different societies working in and out of the university.

Organizational / Managerial skills

Member of Pakistan Society of Food Science and Technology

Food Safety Management, Quality

Control,

Job-related skills

General Management,

Food Production, Quality Lab Management, Quality Assurance, Quality Management,

IPM services, R&D work,

Food Consultancy, MS Offices Operating, Leadership Development Teamwork. Motivational Speaker, Food Safety Trainer, Life Counselor

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION Honors and awards

- Certificate of Excellent services for International States Guest's & Cricket Teams for 2023
- ♣ Certificate of Excellent services for International States Guest's & Cricket Teams for 2024
- ♣ Certificate of Honor in Co-curricular activities of 4th Lyallpur Art and Literature Festival 2016.
- Certificate of Services for Humanity from Sundas Foundation Pakistan in 2015.
- ♣ Certificate for securing 2nd & 3rd position in Chief Minister's Speech/Debate/Essay writing competition in English Speech & Essay Writing at Tehsil level in 2008 and at District level.